

# GARRETT C. MILLAR

UX/HCI RESEARCHER

#### CONTACT



RALEIGH, NC



GCMILLAR.GITHUB.IO



GCMILLAR@NCSU.EDU



(336) 202-5732

#### SKILLS

UX RESEARCH & DESIGN

HCI RESEARCH METHODS

**JAVASCRIPT** 

**PYTHON** 

GIS

STATISTICS

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

DATA VISUALIZATION

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE

#### COURSES

HUMAN FACTORS METHODS STATISTICS I, II, III

ERGONOMIC PERFORMANCE ASSESSMENT

COGNITIVE PROCESSES
PHYSIOLOGICAL PSYCHOLOGY
COGNITIVE SCIENCE

#### PROFILE



A collaborator and researcher with a passion for innovation across a wide variety of platforms. With an inquisitive and empathetic nature, and a background in psychology, computer science, and graphic design, I seek to understand and communicate the human needs, behaviors, motivations, and the physical and cognitive factors that impact the design and function of things. With 8 years in UX / HCI research and design, human interaction, computer science, and design strategy, I bring a strong strategic mindset that connects science and art with a core value of user-centered design.

#### EDUCATION



## 2018 — 2021 | DOCTORATE OF PHILOSOPHY

Geospatial Analytics

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

#### 2016 — 2018 | DOCTORATE OF PHILOSOPHY

Psychology — Human Factors & Applied Cognition North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

#### 2012 — 2016 | BACHELOR OF ARTS

Psychology

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

#### WORK EXPERIENCE



# 2017 — PRESENT | GRADUATE RESEARCH & TEACHING ASSISTANT

O CENTER FOR GEOSPATIAL ANALYTICS — NC STATE UNIVERSITY

- Develop, plan, and manage participatory workshops to understand and resolve user needs encountered during use of a web-mapping platforms.
- Direct design efforts for prototyping and development of web-mapping interfaces through mockups and front-end coding.
- Design and develop visual tools and features for new GUI and startup-screen to enable intuitive software use for all user levels.
- · Assist in the design and implementation of after-school STEM learning program.
- Direct evaluative research efforts for assessing learning outcomes and effectiveness of STEM learning program for high school students.

#### 2016 — 2018 | GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- $\ensuremath{ \bigcirc }$  LABORATORY FOR THE STUDY OF METACOGNITION & ADVANCED LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES
- Designed, developed, and tested interactive multimedia systems with virtual agents to promote college students' STEM learning.
- Built and tested serious gaming environments to increase students' science literacy.

### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS



Millar, G. C., Mitas, O., Boode, W., Hoeke, L., de Kruijf, J., Petrasova, A., & Mitasova, H. (2021). Space-time analytics of human physiology for urban planning. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 85, 101554.

Millar, G. C., Tabrizian P., Petrasova A., Petras V., Harmon B., Mitasova H., Meetenmeyer R. K. (2018). Tangible landscape: A hands-on method for teaching terrain analysis. In Proceedings of the 2018 chi conference on human factors in computing systems (pp. 380:1–380:12). New York, NY, USA: ACM. [Winner of the Honorable Mention for Best Paper Award].

Pryor, M., **Millar, G. C.,** McNamara, A., Kaufman, L., & McLaughlin, A. C. (2017, September). Creating content guidelines for consistent display of information on an ecommerce website. In Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting (Vol. 61, No. 1, pp. 1834-1838). Sage CA: Los Angeles, CA: SAGE Publications.

a,\* Expected defense August 2021.

b,\*\*Transferred from Human Factors and Applied Cognition to Geospatial Analytics in February 2018.